Guide to the Anderson family Papers, 1848-1963
Department of Special Collections
- Robert van Vleck Anderson
  - Letters of Robert van Vleck Anderson to family and Gracella R. Anderson 1927, Jan. - Aug. (Box 52, Folder 523)
  - Letters of Robert van Vleck Anderson to family and Gracella R. Anderson 1927, Aug. - Dec. (Box 52, Folder 524)
  - Letters of Robert van Vleck Anderson to Gracella R. Anderson, 1928 (Box 52, Folder 525)
  - Letters of Robert van Vleck Anderson to Gracella R. Anderson, 1930 (Box 52, Folder 526)
  - Letters of Robert van Vleck Anderson to Melville Best Anderson, 1928-1929-1931 (Box 52, Folder 527)
  - Letters of Robert van Vleck Anderson to Gracella R. Anderson, 1931 (Box 53, Folder 528)
  - Letters of Robert van Vleck Anderson to Gracella R. Anderson, 1932, Jan. - July (Box 53, Folder 529)
  - Letters of Robert van Vleck Anderson to Gracella R, Anderson, 1932, Aug. - Dec. (Box 53, Folder 530)
  - Letters of Robert van Vleck Anderson to Gracella R. Anderson, 1933 (Box 53, Folder 531)
  - Letters of Robert van Vleck Anderson to Gracella R. Anderson and Children, 1934 (Box 53, Folder 532)
  - Letters of Robert van Vleck Anderson to Gracella R. Anderson and Children, 1935 (Box 53, Folder 533)
- Letters of Robert van Vleck Anderson (Box 54)
  - Letters of Robert van Vleck Anderson to Gracella R. Anderson and Children, 1936. (Box 53, Folder 534)
  - Letters of Robert van Vleck Anderson to Gracella R. Anderson and Children, 1937 - 1938 (Box 53, Folder 535)
  - Letters of Robert van Vleck Anderson to Gracella R. Anderson and Children, 1940. (Box 53, Folder 536)
  - Letters of Robert van Vleck Anderson to Gracella R. Anderson and children 1942 (Box 53, Folder 537)
  - Letters of Robert van Vleck Anderson to Gracella R. Anderson and children, 1943, 1944, 1945. (Box 53, Folder 538)
  - Letters of Robert van Vleck Anderson to Gracella R. Anderson, 1946. (Box 53, Folder 539)
  - Letters of Robert van Vleck Anderson to Gracella R. Anderson, 1947 (Box 53, Folder 540)
  - Letters of Robert van Vleck Anderson to Gracella R. Anderson, 1948. (Box 53, Folder 541)
  - Letters of Robert van Vleck Anderson to Gracella R. Anderson, 1949 (Box 53, Folder 542)
  - Letters from J. E. W. Sterling, R. L. Wilbur, Dr. Storey regarding the death of Robert van Vleck Anderson, 1949. (Box 53, Folder 543)
  - General Correspondence of Robert van Vleck Anderson, A - W 1913 - 1915. (Box 55, Folder 544)
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson from Ralph Arnold, 1913 - 1915, Special Folder (Box 55, Folder 545)
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson from J. C. Branner, 1913,., Special Folder (Box 55, Folder 546)
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson from Roderic Crandall, 1913 - 1915, Special Folder (Box 55, Folder 547)
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson from S. Pearson & Son, 1913-1914, Special Folder (Box 55, Folder 548)
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson from S. Pearson & Son, 1915, Special Folder (Box 55, Folder 549)
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson from Arthur Veach (Pearson & Son) 1913 - 1915, Special Folder (Box 55, Folder 550)
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson from. U. S. Geological Survey, 1915, Special Folder (Box 55, Folder 551)
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson from Baily Willis, 1915, Special Folder (Box 55, Folder 552)
  - General Correspondence of Robert van Vleck Anderson, A - W. 1916-20 (Box 55, Folder 553)
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson from Ralph Arnold, 1917 - 1918 (Box 55, Folder 554)
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson from Associated Geological Engineers (Clapp) 1919., Special Folder (Box 55, Folder 555)
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson from Olaf Jenkins, 1919., Special Folder (Box 55, Folder 556)
  - Letter to Robert van Vleck Anderson from Vernon Kellogg, regarding Anderson's letters addressed to Scientific Men of Germany, 1918., Special Folder (Box 55, Folder 557)
  - Letters of Robert van Vleck Anderson regarding Pavlowa Ballet, June, July, 1917. (Box 55, Folder 558)
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson from S. Pearson & Son, 1916, Jan. - July. (Box 55, Folder 559)
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson from S. Pearson & Son, 1916, Aug. - Dec., Special Folder (Box 56, Folder 560)
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson from S. Pearson & Son, 1917, Special Folder (Box 56, Folder 561)
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson from S. Pearson & Son, 1918, Special Folder (Box 56, Folder 562)
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson from S. Pearson & Son, 1919, Special Folder (Box 56, Folder 563)
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson from S. Pearson & Son, 1920, Special Folder (Box 56, Folder 564)
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson from Sinclair Oil Co., 1919., Special Folder (Box 56, Folder 565)
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson from Stanford University 1917, Special Folder (Box 56, Folder 566)
    also #573 #582
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson from U. S. Geological Survey, 1916-1918, Special Folder (Box 56, Folder 567)
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson from Arthur Veach and Roderic Crandall, of Pearson & Son., Special Folder (Box 56, Folder 568)
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson from War Trade Board, 1918 - 1919, Apecial Folder (Box 56, Folder 569)
  - General Correspondence of Robert van Vleck Anderson, A - K, 1921 - 1929 (Box 56, Folder 570)
  - General Correspondence of Robert van Vleck Anderson, L - W 1921 - 1929 (Box 56, Folder 571)
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson. Punjab. 1928 (Box 56, Folder 572)
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Ander on rega ding Stanford University (Box 56, Folder 573)
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson from United States Geological Survey, 1921 (Box 56, Folder 574)
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson from Gerald Westby, Special Folder (Box 56, Folder 575)
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson from Bailey Willis, Special Folder (Box 56, Folder 576)
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson from S. Pearson & Son, 1921, Special Folder (Box 57, Folder 577)
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson from S. Pearson & Son, 1922., Special Folder. (Box 57, Folder 578)
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson, from S. Pearson & Son, 1923 - 1928, Special Folder (Box 57, Folder 579)
  - Letters and telegrams: Wedding of Robert van Vleck Anderson and Gracella Rountree, 1923 (Box 57, Folder 580)
  - General Correspondence of Robert van Vleck Anderson, 1930 - 1948A - Y (Box 57, Folder 581)
  - Letters to Robert van Vleck Anderson regarding Stanford University (Box 57, Folder 582)
  - Robert van Vleck Anderson, Notes on Japan (Box 57, Folder 583)
  - Robert van Vleck Anderson, Copies of letters. Originals to be found in files. (Box 57, Folder 584)
  - Contents (Summary) of letters of Robert van Vleck Anderson (Box 57, Folder 585)
- Pictures and Photographs. (Box 58)
  Friends of the Anderson Family.
  - a Catalog + negatives (Box 57, Folder 586)
  - b. Raymond McDonald Alden (Box 57, Folder 586)
  - Frank Angell
  - Ralph Arnold
  - B. Francis Fisher Browne (Album) (Box 57, Folder 587)
    Children of Francis Fisher Browne
  - C. John Vance Cheney (Box 57, Folder 588)
  - Francis James Child
  - Roderic Crandall
  - D. Maude Damasch (Box 57, Folder 589)
  - Senator Dolph
  - E. W. Ebling (Box 57, Folder 590)
  - F. Ewald Flügel (Box 57, Folder 591)
  - James Failing
  - G. Edward Howard Griggs (Box 57, Folder 592)
  - Mrs. Edward Howard Griggs
  - Graydon -- four groups
  - Katherine Graydon
  - H. Howard Hall (Box 57, Folder 593)
  - Irene Hardy
  - Kate Ala ska Hooper
  - Abby Hutchinson
  - J. Hubert Jenkins (Box 57, Folder 594)
  - J. N. Hall Jackson
  - Mrs. David Starr Jordan (first)
  - David Starr Jordan
  - K. Kiyosh Kanai (Box 59, Folder 595)
  - L. Mrs. L'hote (Box 59, Folder 596)
  - A. A. Lindsley
  - Charles F. Lummis
  - M. Samuel S. McClure (Box 59, Folder 597)
  - Mrs. Samuel S. McClure
  - Mrs. Wanda Muir Hanna
  - Helen Muir Funk
  - N. Evangeline Gossett Newcomer (Box 59, Folder 598)
  - O. Professor Olney (Box 59, Folder 599)
  - Mrs. Olney
  - Niece of Professor Olney
  - P. W. W. Price (Box 59, Folder 600)
  - Adah Peaslee
  - Augustus Parsons
  - S. Daniel Webster Steele (Box 59, Folder 601)
  - Mrs. Minnie Steele
  - L. W. Stephenson
  - Emma Shagrere (Farman)
  - Shinkle
  - James P. Smith
  - V. A. C. Veach (Box 59, Folder 602)
  - W. Lucy Evelyn Wright (Box 59, Folder 603)
  - Lera Winn
  - Frances Walsanbager
  - Anna Strunsky Walling
  - Y. George H. Yost (Box 59, Folder 604)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs: (Box 59, Folder 605)
    Stanford English Department at the time of Melville Best Anderson
    Stanford Geological Society 1906
    Summer School 1895, Hotel de Corona do
    Reunion of Class of 1896, taken in 1921 Transferred to University Archives. 1981
    Interior of Stanford Library 1891
    Palo Alto Daily Staff, Autumn 1901
    The Knyght of the Burning Pestle, 1903 Production of the English Club of Stanford University. Photographs of Stage Sets and Scenes from the play.
- Photographs and Snapshots.
  Family of Melville Best Anderson
  - Melville Best Anderson Photographs and snapshots (Box 59, Folder 606)
  - Melville Best Anderson, Photographs and snapshots, family groups and Menlo Park Home (Box 59, Folder 607)
  - Charlena van Vleck Anderson, Photographs and snapshots (Box 60, Folder 608)
  - Robert van Vleck Anderson Photographs and snapshots (Box 60, Folder 609)
  - Malcolm Playfair Anderson Photographs and snapshots (Box 60, Folder 610)
  - Balfour van Vleck Anderson Photographs and miniature (Box 60, Folder 611)
  - Gertrude Anderson Photographs and snapshots (Box 60, Folder 612)
  - Children of Melville Best Anderson Group Picture (Box 60, Folder 613)
  - Edward Coffin Anderson and Helen Best Anderson, Photograph (Box 60, Folder 614)
- Photographs and Snapshots
  - Edward Playfair Anderson and Family Photographs and snapshots (Box 61, Folder 615)
  - Best Family (Potter, McDonald, Vickery, Hall) Photographs and snapshots (Box 61, Folder 616)
  - Gurnee Family, Photographs and Snapshots (Box 61, Folder 617)
  - van Vleck Family, Photographs and Snapshots (Box 62, Folder 618)
  - Diploma case shelved at end of collection (Othertype 619)
- ADDENDA--Amderson Family Papers
  - Robert van Vleck Anderson (Box 62)
    - Photographs and Negatives. Orient and North Africa. some in duplicate. (Box Envelope #1)
    - Post card pictures -- Russia and Japan
    - Photographs and negatives. California, Nevada and Utah. List of Photographs and explanations. (Box 2)
    - Prints and negatives, South America, Canada and North Africa (Box 3)
    - Prints and Negatives, China. (Box 4)
    - Prints with list. Egypt. (Box 5)
    - Prints with list. Colombia (Box 6)
    - Negatives, Egypt and Miscellaneous (Box 7)
    - Prints, Californis Coast (Box 8)
    - Prints and Negatives -- Costa Rica, Ecuador, Panama, Jamaica, Venezuela, Trinidad, Mexico, Patagonia. (Box 9)
    - Prints and negatives -- India (Box 10)
    - Prints and Negatives -- Ranch (Box 11)
      filed with picture collection
    - Miscellaneous prints and negatives. House in Menlo Park, Stanford, etc. (Box 61, Box 12)
      Some of Edgar A Anderson
      Carmel
      Alpine Road, Santa Clara County
      907 GLASS SLIDES FILED WITH OTHER SLIDES MALCOLM P. ANDERSON MAPS (SEE NEXT PAGE) SENT TO MAP COLLECTION.
      5 photos deaccessioned due to deteriorating emulsion, 28 Oct 1986. (see collection file)
- MAPS USED BY MALCOLM PLAYFAIR ANDERSON JAPAN, CHINA AND KOREA
  40
  - General Map Rand, McNally & Co. (Folder 1)
    War Map of Japan, Korea and China 1904 War Map of Russia and the Continent of Asia.
  - China, 6 Maps. (Folder 2)
    Map of Southern half of Sakhelm Id. legend in Asian script.
    Hakkaido legend in Asian script
    Progress Map of Dignal Corps Telegraph Lines and Cables in the Military Division of the Philippines. Prepared under the direction of Brigadier General A. W. Greely, Chief Signal Officer U. S. Army. Corrected to June 30, 1904.
    Chinese Empire and Japan. London Geographical Institute. General Map of China with route (proposed?) [Possibly Bedford Expedition 1909 - 10]
    Karte von Ost-China Hsi ngan fu Kartegra phische Abteilung der Königl Preusse, Lander-Aufnahme 1902
    Karte von Ost-China Hankow Kartographische Abteilung der Königl Preusse, Lander-Augnahme 1901
  - China, 10 Maps (Folder 3)
    Kitami and Kunajki Is. Asian script
    Karte von Ost China Dolon nor Kartographische Abteilung der Königl Preusse Landes-Aufnahme 1904 Druck 1904
    Karte von Ost-China Mukden Kartographische Abteilung der Königl PreussLandes-Aufnahme 1901 Druck 1904
    Karte von Ost China Nan tschang fu Kartographische Abteilung der Königl Preuss. Landes-Aufnahme 1902
    Unidentified Asian script
    Karte von Ost China Tchung king fu Kartographische Abteilung der Kö¨nigl Preuss. Landes - Aufnahme 1907 Durck 1907
    Karte von Ost China Yi tschang fu Kartographische Abteilung der Königl Preuss. Landes Aufnahme 1902
    Karte von Ost China Tsi nan fu Kartographische Abteilung der Königl Preuss Landes Aufnahms 1901 Druck 1904
    Karte von Ost China Canton Kartographische Abteilung der Königl Preuss Landes Aufnahme 1905 Druck 1905
    Prince Rupert and Vicinity Poole Brothers, Chicago. 1907
  - 2 maps (Folder 4)
    Manchuria, East China and Korea by I. Furukawa and M. Mari The Maruzen Kabushiki Kaisha Tokio and Osaka 1905
    Karte von Ost China Yü lin fu Kartographische Abteilung der Königl Preuss, Landes Affnahme 1902
  - Japan, 4 maps (Folder 5)
    Latest Map of Japan for Travellers by the Welcome Society. Fourth Edition, revised. Tokyo Chamber of Commerce. 1904
    Latest Map of Japan. for Travellers, by the Welcome Society 7th Edition, revised. Chamber of Commerce, Tokyo 1908
    I wate Ken, Japan Asian script
  - Korea, 6 maps (Folder 6)
    Aomeri Prefecture
    Korean Archipelago, Southern Portion. Compiled from Admiralty Surveys made between the years 1845 and 1884 and and from Japanese Government Surveys to 1889. Published at the Admiralty 30th of June, 1871 under the Superintendence of Rear Admiral G. H. Richards, C.B.: F.R.S. Hydrographer. London. Large correction June 1883, Jan. 1886, Nov. 1899, April 1901, Sept. 1901 Soundings in Fathoms. No. 104
    West Coast of Korea Approaches to Seoul with Sir James Hale Group and Ta-Tong River. Tokio. Published at the hydrograph office of the Japanese Naval Department under the superintendence of Rear Adm. N. Yanagi, I. J. N. Hydrographer. 20th March, the 19th year of Meiji (1886) No. 326
    Western Portion of the Japan Sea Compiled from Japanese and Foreign Government Surveys to the 32nd year of Meiji (1889) Magnetic Variation in 1907 Soundings in Fathoms. (Eastern Coast of Korea) No. 179
    Korea - West Coast Tsia Tung Is. to Ping Yang Inlet Compiled fro the Surveys of Commander H. Tokagi, I. J. N., Lts. S. Miura, T. Suzuki and officers of H. M. S. Banjo 22nd - 23rd year of Meiji (1889 - 90). Soundings in Fathoms. No. 332 Tokio - Published at the Hydrographic office 16th of May, 26th year of Meiji (1893) under the superintendence of Capt. M. Yoko-o, I. J. N. Hydrographer.
    Yellow Sea Western Coast of the Korea. Mackau Group to Clifford Islands from partial Surveys by Lieut. R. F. Hoskyn, R. N., 1882 - 1883 and by Capt. J. P. Maclear, R. N. assisted by Lts. G. S. Gunn, H. R. Rooper, H. Baker, W. V. S. Howard and sub Lt. W. O. Lyne, R. N., H. M. S. Flying Fish, 1884 with additions from various Japanese Surveys. No. 913 London - Published at the Admiralty 22nd of February 1886. Under the superintendence of Captain W. J. L. Wharton, R. N. Hydrographer. Large Corrections, May 1900, Feb. 1903
Letters to Melville Best Anderson
- A, Total A 55
  - ALAMS, E.D.
  - Adams, T.C.
  - Alden, Raymond Department of English Stanfod University, 12 (Folder #2)
  - Alden, Barhara Wife of Raymond
  - Alessander, Charlotte
  - Allan, Evelyn Wight. Dean of Women
  - American Museum of Natural History
  - American Consulate
  - American Universities Club of London
  - Amer. Committee for War Relief in Florence
  - Amer. Forestry Asso.
  - Anderson (not family) Nils F.
  - Adnerson, A.J. (President-elect of Whitman College)
  - Anderson, Christina
  - Anspecker
  - Angell, Louise Bayard (wife of Prof Frank Angell - Stanford)
  - Applegater
  - Armes, William Dallam (Prof. English.. U.C.)
  - Armstrong, A.C.
  - Authors Club
  - Avery Brothers
  - Ayer, Clarence
  - E.P. Anderson
  - H. B. Anderson
- B, Total B 549
  - Branner, John Caspar 1904- 1914Stanford-- Gellogy Dept., 6 (Folder #3)
    Member of Old Guard (first professors at Stanford) M.B.A. and Branner students together at Cornell. Advice concerning Robert van Vleck Anderson, who was majoring in Geology....family news... comments on David Starr Jordan and administration at Stanford.. jingles about Stanford. Etc.
  - Bade, William 1917Pacific School of Religion-Berkeley. (regarding John Muir), 11 (Folder 4)
  - Baker, Bancroft
  - Bannister, L.W. (Lawyer. Palo Alto
  - Barnhisel. Property investment in Tacoma, Washington.
  - Bassett, Lee Emerson. Stanford-- English Department
  - Bateman, Newton. President Knox College, 10
  - Barmeyer, W. French correspondent.
  - Beach, Auguste J.C. German correspondent.. Gottingen, Germany. To CvvA, 20
  - Bennett, Malivina Student.. of M.B.A.... Dante, 12
  - Beavis, Arthur
  - Beckwith, Daniel
  - Bender, Victor re; lecture series., 5
  - Berger, A.K. re: publications of M.B.A. edition of (China) American Museum of Natural History (Folder 5)
  - Bartell, Rosina faithful servant.. in Florence, Italy.
  - Bille, Anna grateful student.. tribute to M.B.A.
  - Bills, Claire grateful student
  - Binkley, C.K. colleague.. Dante.
  - Blodgett, Benjamin.. musician... friend of M.B.A., 5
  - Bohemian Club of San Francisco 1892-1893-1894 transient member bills
  - Bonnell, Jack gifted student of M.B.A. at Knox College., 16
  - Boring, Ore Teacher.U.S. Naval Academy. Dante.
  - Boyd, W.R.
  - Boyle, Evelyn H. re: Malcolm Playfair Anderson
  - Bradley, C.B. English Dept. University of California, 12 (Box 8A, Folder #6)
  - Bradshaw, J.W.
  - Brayton, Dr. A.W. friend.. University of Purdue, 16
  - Brenker, Ida re: Poem of M.B.A. Happy Teacher
  - Brewer, Rev. William. Episcopalian Minister..San Mateo..card (visiting)
  - Bright, James John Hopkins University-Dept of Modern Language, 7
  - Briggs, william Dinsmore Mills College.. Dept. of English.
  - Brinton, Howard husband of Anna Cox Brinton. Gifted student of M.B.A.
  - Brinbecomar, Charles letter of appreciation.
  - Bristol, Susan
  - Browne, Andrew Stanford Faculty.
  - Brown, D.C. 1884Butler University..Irvington Indiana, 5
  - Brown H. re: Happy Teacher
  - Brusie, Charles 1893re: post at Stanford.. English Dept.
  - Bucciolini, Audio 1912Italian correspondence... Florence, Italy.
  - Bullock, Mary birthday note on 70th birthday of M.B.A.
  - Bunce, Helen Beece 1995Friend...Italy.
  - Burnham, Merie Sophrene 1921birthday note on 70th birthday of M.B.A.
  - Bunker, Ida 1881-1885friend...,Chicago., 10
  - Burke, Mary 1895Student of M.B.A.
  - Burr, George 1892re: position..from Cornell University.
  - Burrell, H.H. Washington County Press
  - Burritt, Elizebeth 1921former student of M.B.A.
  - Burt, Mary 1887-1895re: advice for children's reading., 5
  - Butler, Prof. Scot 1881 - 1895Irvington, Indians
  - Browne, Francis F. Browne 1881-1913Editor of the Dial, 392
    intimate friend and colleague of M.B.A. Advisor..confident...Publisher of French Classics (translator-M.B.A.)
    - letter from MBA - Date uncertain
    - letter from MBA June 28, 1886
    - letter from MBA May 18-1913
  - Browne, Weldo R. son of F.F. Browne, 9
- C, total C 242
  - Caldwell, Edith re: Florence, Italy
  - Caldwell, Mary Lucile Student
  - California State Library
  - Calvin, Alice 1895death of Balfour Anderson
  - Cambridge University Press 1911Encyclopedia Britennics (purchase)
  - Camp, Grece 1919-1921funeral of Malcolm P. Anderson
  - Campbell, Mary G. 1895Balfour.
  - Carnegie Foundation re: M.B.A. pension.
  - Carruth, W.H. 1919Dept. of English-Stanford. re: Malcolm
  - Carson, E.T. 1888re: translation of Victor Eugo
  - Caxton Club re: publishing notes of M.B.A.-Joutel's Journal.
  - Chandler, Katherine student, 5
  - Chandler, A.C. 1887Secretary Board of Trustees.. Mc Minnville College.. re: return of Edward Coffin Anderson as President (E.C.A. -father of M.B.A.)
  - Chapman, Berthe Student
  - Chapman, F.A. 1892Colorado College re: position
  - Charles, Shirley 1905Accepts invitation for lunch. Student.
  - Cheney, Abby 1892friendly note., 30
  - Cheney, John Venee 1892Death of Gertrude Anderson. Colleague. Newberry Library-Chicago., 30
  - Choiseul, Mme de Charming friend, whom M.B.A. visited in Paris.
  - Clark and Maynard Book Dealers.
  - Clark, Fred request for teaching post
  - Clark, Mary grateful student
  - Cleland, Elizebeth 1887request to leave M.B.A. speak at her Club.
  - Cleland, Joe
  - Cook, Prof. Albert Stanburrough 1888-1911colleague Johns Hopkins University of Jens, University of California, Yale, 33
    Put in special folder.
  - Comstock, John Henry Prof. of Entomology, Cornell.
  - Cook, E.K. 1892Colleague..Univ. of Iowa
  - Cook, George C Iowa.. grateful student, 8
  - Cook, M.L. grateful student.
  - Coolidge, Dane 1910-1919writer... California, 5
  - Coombs, Susan Bird 1921student.
  - Cooper, Alice
  - Couse, Mary E. 1880student., 5
  - Cousins, Robert 1888attorney- appreciation.
  - Cox, Anna and Lydia Charles. 1911-1914students of M.B.A. Stanford. gifted family., 20
  - Creig, Oscar 1886Purdue University, 10
  - Crane, F.F. 1873-1890Ithica..Cornell..Professional advice about Germany., 15
  - Crum William 1889lawyer., 12
  - Culver, Louise Stanford., 3
  - Culler, Leland Stanford.
  - Cyclist Touring Club
  - Cassot, Arthur
    Special Folders
  - La Marchesa Mannuci Capponi née Agnes Smith. Special student at Stanford. Came from environs of Los Angeles., 9
    letters, sketches (word) Picture The Beatrice in life of M.B.A.
  - Creig, Edward Gordon Son of great English actress. Ellen Terry 1915-1922, 33
- D, Total D 48
  - Davidson, Cassie 1905grateful student, 3
  - Davis, Katharine T. 1921grateful student
  - Dammasch, Sarah 1895letter of sympathy (Balfour)
  - Day, K.A. 1887friends.. Indiana, 5
  - De Graff, Ellen Ames 1894friends.. Worcester, Mass.
  - De Laguns, Frederika student-friend. later wife of William (?) Street.. 2 Stanfrod daughtars.
  - Dickey, Mary Nelson 1907friend. travelling in Florence., 5
  - Dietz, Jane 1890Iowa City, 5
    (ref. to Mrs. Veblen) to Mrs. Anderson
  - Dickinson, Evelina 1895Wilmington, Del.
  - Dudley, William 1895congratulatory letter (poetry)
  - Duff, James 1916congratulatory letter (poetry)
  - Duncan, 1890-1891re: course of lectures of M.B.S. Sheffleld, Illinois., 6
    Special Folder.
  - Emma Frances Dawson 1892-1917Poetress, colleague, friend of family, 15
- E, Total E 76
  - Eaton, Will 1876Editor-Kalamazoo Telegraph, 2
  - Eaves, Lucile 1921Director Research Department - Women's Education and Industrial Union. Student
  - Ebeling, W. Prof. 1876 1891German. responsible for housing Charlene van Vleck Anderson and 4 children., 25
    in Eisleben for 2 years. controlled the boys education. great factor in family. Letters in German. Should be read to properly evaluate the effect of this experience on Anderson family. M.B.A. never forgave C.v V.A. for the death of little Gertrude, which he attributed to the poor housing and unsatisfactory conditions in Germany.
    To both MBA and CvVA.
  - Edwards, Ellen S. 1882request for advice (student), 3
  - Eliot, Charles 1893Pres. Harvard University-to D. S. Jordan regarding MLA, 1
  - Elliot, A.M. Johns Hopkins, 10
  - Elliot, O.L. 1886 1891Stanford..Sec. to President., 3
  - Elmore, Jefferson 1914-1921Stanford University.. Prof. of Latin. Praise of poem of M.B.A., 4